Madhuri Dhamodey

React Native Developer

As a skilled software development professional with 2+ years of experience, I bring a wealth of talent in software design, development, and integration with advanced knowledge of in-demand programming languages. My background includes extensive experience in React Native, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java and production-grade applications, demonstrating my expertise in meeting industry-specific requirements.



- madhuri.dhamodey@gmail.com
- Pengaluru, India
- in linkedin.com/in/madhuri-dhamodey

- +91-9380444911 / +91-9424314993
- madhuri-dhamodey.netlify.app/
- github.com/madhuri-dhamodey

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Engineer

Noetic IT Services 12/2020 - 06/2022

Description

- Took complete ownership of developing **Apnatok** it is a social media app. Designed various components to enhance the UI/UX of the application.
- Implemented Mobx State Tree to ensured a streamlined flow of data, enabling enhanced performance and maintainability; reducing their load time by 37% and increasing user engagement rates by 25%.
- Designed intuitive user interfaces with native UI elements, including navigation drawers, search bars & custom icons compatible across multiple devices without compromising any functionalities or aesthetic appeal.
- Tech stack React Native, Redux, Mobx, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

React Native Developer

Corpusvision Technologies

07/2020 - 11/2020

Achievements/Tasks

- Refactored existing React Native codebase to enhance stability, reduce memory consumption and improve the overall user experience; increased mobile app performance by 40% in 3 months.
- Structured reusable UI components based on custom design specifications in order to optimize coding efficiency and maintain high-quality standards throughout the project duration; reduced bug count by 20%.

Software Developer Intern

Engineer Master Solution (EMS)

02/2020 - 04/2020

Achievements/Tasks

• Collaborated with the development team to implement basic features, conduct bug fixes, and carry out testing in React Native projects. Gained valuable experience in mobile app development, and action-oriented problem-solving.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Online Mobile Store React.js | Paypal Express

10/2019 - 12/2019

Description

- Led e-commerce website development, facilitating secure transactions and effortless mobile device discovery. Leveraged React.js to create dynamic, interactive UI components, expediting and simplifying web development.
- Project Link:- https://react-e-commerce-md.netlify.app/

SKILLS

React Native HTML5 CSS MvSOL Spring Boot JavaScript ReactJs

EDUCATION

LNCT, Bhopal | MCA (2018)

Course - Master of Computer Applications (8.55)

VVM College, Betul (MP) | BSC (2016) Branch:- Computer Science (69.4)

CERTIFICATES

Complete React Native Course (Udemy) (06/2020 - Present)

EXTRA-CURRICULAR

Runner-up in sketching competition in a National Level Tech-Fest. (2017)

LNCT, Bhopal (MP)

Runner-up in TREASURE HUNT (Google) which was powered by Mozilla. (2017)

LNCT, Bhopal (MP)

Won the College Level Team Dance Competition.

VVM College, Betul

INTERESTS

Sketchina

Art & Craft

Reading Books